准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
现在播出的是  派斯精选
And now it's time for Patchy's Pick
派斯精选
主持人是海绵宝宝的头号粉丝
hosted by SpongeBob's number one fan
海盗派斯
Patchy the Pirate
你们好  粉丝同伴们
Ahoy, fellow fanatics
欢迎收看派斯精选
Welcome to Patchy's Pick
要不你们来厨房吧
Why don't you come on back to the galley?
我今天在给你们整点消遣的
I'm cooking up a real treat for you today
骗上贼船
我们要来看我最爱的节目  骗上贼船
We're going to see me favorite show, Shanghaied
无聊
Boring
这不就是我的没意思小跟班
Well, if it isn't my less than amusing sidekick
鹦鹉波蒂吗
Potty the Parrot?
波蒂  跟观众们打个招呼
Potty, say hello to the nice people
我是被强行关押在这的
I'm being held here against my will
救命
Help
波蒂
Potty
快回来
Come back
波蒂
Potty?
你哪去了
Where'd you go?
波蒂
Potty?
你在里面吗  兄弟
You in there, buddy?
波蒂
Potty?
放我出去  你个坏鸟
Get me out of here, you scurvy bird
好  播动画片
Well, roll the cartoon
骗上贼船
导演
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
海草哥麦片
Kelpo
内含八个奖品之一
"With one of eight essential prizes inside"
真是见鬼了
Holy Shrimp
章鱼哥
Squidward
上天从我麦片盒里生小孩了
The sky had a baby from my cereal box
章鱼哥
Squidward
上天生小孩了
The sky had a baby
那个不是小孩  是大锚
That's not a baby, that's a giant anchor
现在给我滚
Now, go away
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
上天生小孩了
The sky had a baby
我知道
I know
你说该给人家起什么名
What do you think we should name it?
要么
How about?
要不你们两个去爬锚绳去
Why don't you two go climb its anchor rope?
它一定会通往很远的地方去
I'm sure it goes somewhere far away
看看你们干的好事
Now look what you've done
不是我们干的  章鱼哥
We didn't do it, Squidward
我们可清白了
Our hands are clean
清白
Clean
我倒要刨根问底查个明白
Well, I'm going to get to the bottom of this thing
那不是问顶吗
Wouldn't that be the top?
章鱼哥  等等
Squid, wait
章鱼哥
Squidward
几英寸后
船
Ship
海绵宝宝  你到底要胡思乱想多久
SpongeBob, how long are you going to stay
in your little fantasy world?
不是  快看
No, look
真的有大船
a giant ship
太棒了  我们走
Great, let's go
终于能给这乱扔大锚的来一点教训了
Now I can finally give this anchor-dropper
a piece of my mind
感觉不太好  章鱼哥
I don't know, Squidward
那艘船周围有可怕的绿光
That ship has a spooky green glow around it
可能就是因为
That's probably because
船主实在是游手好闲
its good-for-nothing owner is too lazy
懒得打扫  锚也不好好放
to clean or drop his anchors in the right place
章鱼哥  等等
Squid, wait
谁是这木头箱子的主人
All right, who owns this crate?
主人
快出来
Come on out
我要投诉你
I want to file a complaint
这地方是不是感觉很熟悉
Doesn't this place seem familiar?
不清楚
I don't know
怎么了
why?
不好说
l don't know
感觉就是有那么点印象
Doesn't it just kind of ring a bell?
响 铃
没错
Yes
我知道谁是这船的主人
I know who owns this boat
就是想不起名字
I just can't place the name
飞天魔鬼所有
错了  名字不叫
No, no, it's not
我是飞天魔鬼
I am the Flying Dutchman
对了
That's it
章鱼哥  这船是红男爵的
This ship belongs to the Red Baron
是谁胆敢在飞天魔鬼的地盘打扰人家
Who be disturbing the Flying Dutchman in his own lair?
是章鱼哥
lt's Squidward
他要投诉你
He wants to complain to you
我我我
I-I-I
我可可可没有
No, I-I-I don't
那你骂人家船脏人懒又是怎么一回事
Well, what about all that stuff about him
having a dirty ship and being lazy and all?
我可没说过
I-I never said that
侮辱一个人的船
Insulting a man's ship
比侮辱一个人的妈更严重
be worse than insulting his mother
错了  等下
No, no, wait
你刚骂的是他妈脏
it was his mother you said was dirty
不是船脏
not his ship
下一个是你们
You're next
真是差一点就死了
That was a close one
欢迎回来
Welcome back
真是差一点点就死了
That was a closer one
欢迎回来
Welcome back
他们两个怎么每次捣乱
How come when they act up
你都要欢迎
all they get is the welcome wagon?
要我说  早就
If you ask me, it's
所以你们要不要再来一次
So are you going to try that again?
也许吧
Probably
那现在呢
How about now?
不对  他们不要
No, no, they're not
听好了
Now listen
鬼矩手册
无论是谁登上了飞天魔鬼的船
"Whosoever sets foot on the Flying Dutchman's ship
不管是不是不请自来
"uninvited or otherwise
都要成为他的鬼水手  一辈子
"shall become members of his ghostly crew forever
然后
and, uh
永远
ever"
我们会领名片吗
Will we be getting business cards?
别吵
Silence
你们现在是我的鬼水手了
You're part of my crew now
我们的工作就是四处航行吓唬别人
and our job is to sail around and frighten people
会很累人  麻木人
lt'll be grueling, mind-numbing
还反反复复的
and repetitive
差不多就像
Just like
白天的电视节目
daytime television
现在你给我听好  先生
Now, you listen here, mister
你要是真觉得我会
If you think I'm going to
在这垃圾堆里待个五分钟以上
spend more than five minutes on this dumpster
你就想多了
then you're crazy
倒是看看这地方
I mean, look at this place
恶心死了
It's disgusting
是谁教你
Whoever told you
一定要把油灯放硬木板边上
that hanging oil lamps
next to hardwood paneling was a good idea
怎么
Now what?
要给我看东西
I suppose you're going to show me
真是好好看
Gee, that's very nice
这什么玩意  魔术表演吗
What is this, some kind of magic act?
谁还要进去飞天绝望里玩一玩
Would anyone else like to enter the Fly of Despair?
不用了
No
我们明白自己地位了  飞天魔鬼先生
we know our place now, Mr. Dutchman
我们会照你说的做的
We'll do anything you say
那么你们俩新来的可以  擦甲板
Then for starters, you can swab the deck
快看  派大星
Look, Patrick
活生生的鬼拖把
a real, live ghost mop
我有这顶帽子
And I got this hat
听着
Listen
我们今晚要去裤头村
We're heading down to Bikini Bottom tonight
来闹个鬼
for a little haunting spree
所以我要这艘船的外观非常吓人
so I want this ship to look good and scary
你是说你要船的外观非常
You mean you want it to look good
吓人
and scary
我们也许可以
Well, I think we could probably
错了
No, no
人家说的是要外观特别好
I think he means he wants it to look so good
好到可怕的地步
that it's scary
或者可能是让船的外观很吓人
Or maybe that by looking so scary
就可以忽略掉船很难看了
you forget that it doesn't look good
我听不懂
I don't get it
很简单的
Look, it's easy
意思就是
It simply means
别管什么意思了
Never mind what it means
样子吓人就行
I just want it to look scary
仅此而已
That's it
就是那种
You know
天花板发霉  水池里有虫爬的
mold growing on the ceilings, bugs in the sink
所以你不要船好看吗
So, you don't want it to look good?
快点干
Get moving
水手的命儿真是妙
A sailor's life is a wonderful life
命儿实在妙
A wonderful life for sure
今晚夜色真美
What a night be this
水手们  跟我嚎叫
Crew, howl with me
让七大洋颤栗吧
so that we might set the seven seas ablaze with fear
可以了
That'll do
好了  方家伙
Okay, square one
既然粉家伙在负责航行
Since pink one's working the navigation
就让你来找我们第一个受害者
it's up to you to find our first victim
给  用这把望远镜找
Here, use this spyglass
动作快
Now, hurry up
时间不等人
We're burning moonlight
看看能找到谁
Let's see who we can find
船长  那边那位可以吓
Captain, there's a guy we can scare
我有四块饼干  吃掉了一个
I had four biscuits, and I ate one
就只有三块了
Then I only had three
看到有小孩子夜不归宿让我开心死了
It does me heart good to see children out after dark
粉家伙  给我们带到石头后边去
Pink one, take us behind those rocks
到石头后边去
Moving behind the rocks
开走
Keep going
很好  很好
You're good, you're good
再
And
停
stop
放心  船长
Don't worry, Cap'n
我们会把划痕弄干净的
We'll buff out those scratches
好了  那个别管了
All right, never mind it
我给暗号你们就跳出来
Just jump out when I give the signal
做好准备
Prepare to be burdened
让我的鬼海盗们留下挥之不去的阴影
with the haunting memory of my ghostly ghost pirates
暗号就那
Was that the signal?
好的  抱歉抱歉
Okay, sorry, sorry
再来一遍
Just do it again
让我的鬼海盗们留下挥之不去的阴影
With the haunting memory of my ghostly ghost pirates
怎么做到的
How does he do that?
快回船上去
Get back on the ship
这还是个谜
It's still a mystery
那些人真是笨蛋
Those guys are dorks
对  不过是我的笨蛋
Yes, but they're my dorks
很好  很好
You're good, you're good
很好
You're good
很好  很好
You're good, you're good
你觉得飞天魔鬼干嘛
Why do you think the Dutchman
叫我们在卧铺里等啊
asked us to wait in our bunk room?
可能是他要给我们奖励
Maybe he's going to give us a reward
比如说电影票吗
Like movie passes?
或者是超大咖啡杯
Or an oversized coffee mug
经过考虑
I've been thinking
别跳了
Stop bouncing
让你们一辈子当我船员好像行不通
This whole "crew for eternity" thing isn't working out
与其说是你们的问题  不如说是我的
It's not really you, so much as it is me
你要放了我们吗
You're setting us free?
其实吧  我要吃掉你们
Well, actually, I'm just going to eat you
晩餐见
See you at dinner
等等
Wait
我有个办法
I have an idea
真的吗
Really?
是什么
What is it?
逃走吧
Let's leave
可是门锁上了
But the door is locked
唯一的出路是穿过
And the only way out is through the
香水商店
perfume department
就这么干了
Let's do it
我讨厌从那走
I always hate going in there
没错
Yeah
等等  你听
Wait, listen
亲爱的日记
Dear Diary
我跟他们讲我明天要吃掉他们
l've told them I'm going to eat them tomorrow
我做了那种棕酱
l made up some of that brown sauce
先前我表哥临时给我看过
my cousin showed me just for the occasion
又找着我的饭点袜了  可真是好事
It's a good thing I found my dining sock again
还记得我上次丢了饭点袜不
Remember the last time I lost me dining sock?
当时我一整个星期都吃不下饭
I couldn't eat for a whole week
是啊  有时我在想要是碰巧出了事
Yes, sir, sometimes I wonder how I survive
我还怎么好好过日子
If anything should ever happen
把我袜子还回来
Give me back my sock
大家都清楚我没袜子吃不下饭
Everyone knows I can't eat without it
不给
Never
那好
Okay, then
给我
Give it to me
不给
No
等等
Wait
你会把弹性拉没的
You're stretching out the elastic
好像陷入僵局了
It would seem we have reached an impasse
粉家伙说得对
Pink one is right
跟你们说
Tell you what
你们把袜子还我  我就给你们
you give me back the sock and I'll give you
三个愿望
three wishes
要五个
Make it five
四个
Four
三个
Three
不要就拉倒
Take it or leave it
好吧
Okay
三个
three
你们有三个愿望
You get three wishes
有三个愿望  派大星
Three wishes, Pat
是不是很棒啊
Isn't that great?
愿望
Wishes?
真希望能早点知道
I wish we had known that earlier
好了  你们就剩下两个愿望了
Okay, you got two wishes left
好啦  还有两个
Well, we still have two more
好激动啊
How exciting
真希望章鱼哥能来亲眼目睹
I wish Squidward were here to see this
真高兴一切都结束了
Boy, I'm glad all that's over
章鱼哥  你回来了
Squidward, you're back
你猜怎么着
Guess what
飞天魔鬼给了我们三个愿望
The Dutchman gave us three wishes
派大星用了第一个
Patrick used the first one
我好像
and I guess I
用掉了第二个
just used the second one
那么最后一个是你们欠我的
Well, then the last one you owe me
因为你们又把我拖下水了
because you got me back into this mess
慢着  愿望应该是我的
Wait, I think it belongs to me
都够了
That's enough
用我的神秘超凡力量
Using my mystic otherworldly powers
由我来决定最后一个愿望归谁
I shall decide who gets the last wish
咿呢咪呢唛呢哞  抓住水手脚趾头
Eenie-meenie-minie-mo, catch a sailor by the toe
如果大叫放他走
If he hollers, let him go
我妈教导我要挑最好的那个
My mother told me to pick the very best one and
就
You
你
are
了
it
现在快想  海绵宝宝
Now, think, SpongeBob
我们就要被吃掉了
We're about to get eaten
你可以许什么愿望
What can you wish for
可以让我们不被吃掉
to make it so we don't get eaten?
放心  章鱼哥
Don't worry, Squidward
我都想明白了
I've got it all figured out
他不会吃掉我们的
He won't be able to eat us
因为我希望飞天魔鬼是吃素的
because I wish that the Dutchman was a vegetarian
万岁
Hooray
我们回家了
We're home
成功了  海绵宝宝
You did it, SpongeBob
我们安全了
We're safe
可我们为什么变水果了
But why have we been turned into fruits?
我也许了个愿
I get a wish, too
水果可以预防坏血病
And fruit prevents scurvy
快给我回来
Get back here with that
我要逮着你们
I'll get you
孩子们好
Ahoy, children
我回来了
I'm back
希望你们大家都非常喜欢刚刚的节目
I hope all you boys and girls enjoyed the show
因为你们现在必须走甲板落海身亡了
because it's time for you to walk the plank
请稍候
抱歉  孩子们
Sorry, kids
我想说的是
What I meant to say was
现在要来读粉丝来信了
it's time for fan mail
万岁
Hooray
现在  万众期待的时刻
And now, the moment you've all been waiting for
准备好把牛奶从鼻子里喷出来吧
So get ready to blow milk out your nose
因为我们要拆信了
because we're going to open a letter
信封拿来  波蒂
The envelope please, Potty
谢谢  我长羽毛的好助理
Thank you, my fine feathered assistant
用不着你谢
You're not welcome
波蒂  闻到什么了没
Potty, you smell something?
波蒂
Potty
你脑袋装了引信
That fuse in your head
都说过不耍特技了
I told you, we're not doing that stunt
我没收到备忘录
I didn't get the memo
派斯精选到此结束
Well, that's it for Patchy's Pick
给小蜗洗澡
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
小蜗  又到了每周必经的时间了
Gary, looks like it's that time of week again
洗澡时间
Bath time
走吧  去把水准备好
Come on, let's go get the water started
一定要让你进浴缸里去  小蜗
You're going to have to get in that tub, Gary
小蜗  我可以给你来硬的
Now, Gary, we can do this the hard way
也可以来软的
or the easy way
也可以来软硬适中的
Or the medium way
也可以来半适中软硬的
Or the semi-medium, easy-hard way
也可以来硬中带软外加软硬皆施的
Or the sort of hard with a touch of
awkward-easy difficult-challenging way
你非要这么玩是吧
So that's how you want to play it, huh?
小蜗  来看这个新玩具
Gary, check out this new toy
去捡
Fetch
全新回旋宠物球
New boomerang pet ball
十分有效
Really works
小蜗
Gary
我胸口绑了一颗炸弹
There's a bomb strapped to my chest
你不去洗澡  三秒就会爆炸
It's gonna explode in three seconds
unless you take a bath
求你了
Please?
我要用潜意识信息侵入你的心智
I am now going to assault your mind
with subliminal messages
肥皂
抱歉让你看到那种画面
Sorry you had to see that
喂  法式贵族餐厅吗
Hello, fancy French restaurant?
我这边有只不洗澡的淘气蜗牛
I've got a naughty snail here who won't take a bath
什么
What?
能再说一遍吗
Could you say that again?
说慢点
Slow down
你讲话就跟说外语似的
It's like you're speaking some other language
小蜗
Hey, Gare
要不要来跳山羊
How 'bout some leap frog?
好
OK
到你了
You're turn
小蜗
Gare
要不要来跳山羊
How 'bout some leap frog?
我有张崭新干净的一块钱
I've got a crisp dollar bill
要送给家里洗澡的人
for the next fella to take a bath in this house
那样也没用是吧
That didn't work either, huh?
小蜗
Gary
看我找到了什么
Look what I found
是张古老海盗藏宝图
It's an old pirate treasure map
上面写着家里埋海盗宝藏的位置
revealing the location of
buried pirate treasure in this very house
不是浴室
埋藏的宝藏
小蜗快来
Come on, boy
一起去寻宝吧
Let's go get that treasure
好了  小蜗
OK, Gary
向左四十步
Now 40 paces to the left
一
One
二
two
三
three
四
four
五
five
六
six
七
seven
八
eight
九
nine
十
ten
十一
eleven--
宝藏一定就在里面
The treasure must be in here
小蜗你看
Gary, look
海盗宝箱
A pirate treasure chest
不对  小蜗
Why, no, Gary
这可不是浴缸
This isn't the bathtub
是宝藏
It's treasure
你看
Look
金币
Doubloons
肥皂
别扔了
Don't drop 'em
快看这枚胸针
Look at this brooch
我不知道蜗牛要胸针干什么用
I don't know what a snail would want with a brooch
你快进浴缸里去吧
Now, why don't you just get in the tub?
进浴缸里去
Get in the tub
进浴缸
In the tub
小蜗  你要么给我进浴缸
Now, Gary, are you going to get in this tub
要么我就
or am I gonna have to--
小蜗
Gary
你能不能
Could you, uh--
小蜗  不要
Gary, no
小蜗
Gary
好了  小蜗
All right, Gary
你再也骗不到我  也阻挠不到我了
You have duped and/or frustrated me for the last time
要是我没办法让你来洗澡
So if I can't get you to come to the bath
我就只能让澡来洗你了
I'll just have to bring the bath to you
蜗牛笑话
小蜗
Gary
洗澡快递
Bath delivery
回来  小蜗
Come back, Gary
我有东西要给你分享
I have something to share with you
这还差不多
This is more like it
你在等水啊  小蜗
Water you waiting for, Gary?
在树上下不来了
Stuck in a tree?
现在要让你洗心革面了  小蜗
It's time to clean up your act, Gary
完了
Oh, no
我把小蜗洗过头了
I bathed Gary too hard
把小蜗皮洗没了
and removed his skin
小蜗
Gary
马上把梯子放回去
Bring that ladder back this instant
一点都不好笑  先生
I am really not amused, mister
你一定得洗澡
You are going to take a bath
而且一定得马上洗干净
and you are going to get clean right now
我可是你的老板
I am so the boss of you
这里也许是个自由的国家
It may be a free country
但你住我家  就必须按我的规矩办事
but you live in my house, under my rules
不许对我用那样的口气说话
Don't use that tone of voice with me
我说什么你就得做什么
You will do what I say, when I say
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我跟你说话呢  先生
I am talking to you, mister
不准靠近那个泥坑
Do not go near that mud puddle
蜗牛小蜗  你听没听到
Gary the Snail, do you hear me?
给你三秒钟的时间
I am giving you three seconds
让你离泥坑远点
to get away from that mud puddle
一
One
二
two
二点五
two and a half
别逼我数到三
Don't make me say three
小蜗
Gary
我全身脏透了
I'm a dirty boy
好了  小蜗
Yeah, yeah, Gary
在洗我耳朵背面了
I'm getting behind my ears